hays.com 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy | US jobs and recruitment | Hays

If you do not agree to our processing of your data in the manner outlined in the Policy, **please do not submit any personal data to us**.

### Who is the controller of the data that you provide to us?

Hays Specialist Recruitment Limited and its operating affiliates are registered as data controllers in the United Kingdom for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998. We ensure that the data you supply to us is processed fairly and lawfully, and with skill and care and used only for the purposes set out in this policy.

### What information will we collect? How will we use it?

We will collect data about you, both personal data (such as your name and contact details) and also sensitive personal data (such as information in your resume). The personal data and sensitive personal data will be stored, processed, used and disclosed by us in the following ways:

•    To provide our recruitment services to you and to facilitate the recruitment process  
•    To assess data about you against vacancies which we judge may be suitable for you  
•    To send your information to clients in order to apply for jobs or to assess your eligibility for jobs  
•    To enable you to submit your resume, apply online for jobs or to subscribe to alerts about jobs we think may be of interest to you  
•    To allow you to participate in online training services  
•    To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service when you choose to do so  
•    To market our full range of recruitment services to you (search, temporary, and recruitment process outsourcing services)  
•    To enable us to develop and market other products and services and where you have consented to being contacted for such purposes  
•    To improve our customer service and to make our services more valuable to you (including tailoring our website and our group companies websites when you log on to enrich your personal online experience)  
•    To send you details of reports, promotions, offers, networking and client events and general information about the industry sectors which we think might be of interest to you where you have consented to being contacted for such purposes  
•    To answer your questions   
•    To third parties  we have retained to provide services that you or our client have requested such as references, qualifications and criminal background checking services, verification of the details you have provided from third party sources, psychometric evaluations or skill tests  
•    To third parties who perform functions on our behalf and who also provide services to us, such as professional advisors, IT consultants carrying out testing and development work on our business systems, research and mailing houses and outsourcing partners.  
•    To regulatory or law enforcement agencies if we believe in good faith that we are required by law to disclose it in connection with the detection of crime, the collection of taxes or duties, in order to comply with any applicable law or order of a court of competent jurisdiction, or in connection with legal proceedings  
•    To use your information on an anonymized basis to monitor compliance with our equal opportunities policy  
•    To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us or between us and our clients

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please check the relevant box  on the form on which we collect your data. Where there is no such box we will use your data as stated in this Privacy Policy.

From time to time we may seek your consent to process, use or disclose your information for any other purpose not listed above.  
We may also pass your information to, or allows access to such information to the Hays group of companies, whose locations can be found at [www.haysplc.com](https://www.haysplc.com/) in order that they may use your personal information in the same way as we process, use and disclose your information as described above.

We reserve the right to transfer your information to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Policy and provided that the third party only uses your Personal Data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt-out.

### Where will my information be held? Where will it be accessible from?

The personal information that you provide to us (including sensitive personal information) may be accessible by other Hays group companies, clients, and the third parties specified above. Some of these Hays companies, clients and third parties are located outside of the United States. Accordingly your personal information will be sent to or be capable of being accessed from outside the United States. When we transfer your personal information outside the United States we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Privacy Policy.  

### How do I find out what information you hold? Can I amend, modify or require my information to be deleted? Can I unsubscribe to your services?

You may request us to confirm what information we hold about you at any time and may request us to modify, update or delete such information. We may ask you to verify your identity and for more information about your request. We also have the right to charge an administrative fee for this service. Where we are legally permitted to do so, we may refuse your request and will give you reasons for doing so. We will seek to act on your request in the timescale required by applicable data protection laws.

_If you no longer wish to receive job alerts, marketing and promotional emails from Hays U.S., please click the unsubscribe link included in the footer of the email you received.   If you wish to contact us with any other matters, please email us at feedback-us@hays.com_.

Hays U.S Corporate Office is located at 4350 West Cypress Street, Suite 1000, Tampa FL 33607.

### How long will you hold my information for?

We are required by law to hold your information for as long as is necessary to comply with our statutory and contractual obligations and in accordance with our legitimate interests as a data controller.

We will use reasonable endeavors to ensure that your Personal Data is maintained and up to date. However, you are under a duty to inform us of any and all changes to your Personal Data to ensure that it is up to date and we will update or delete your Personal Data accordingly. 

### Sending us information over the internet

Your information is held on servers hosted by us or our Internet Services Provider. The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

### How we collect and aggregate information about visitors to our websites

We also collect information about the way job seekers and visitors use this website in order to improve our services. We do not use information gained in this manner in a way that any individual can be identified, and will use it to understand our users better, and to determine aggregate trends, most popular pages, etc, for all the website’s users. We may share this kind of aggregate data with selected third parties to assist with these purposes where you have consented to this. We may also undertake marketing profiling to help us identify services or jobs which may be of interest to you.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small data file which is sent from a web server to a web browser when that browser visits the server’s site. We obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored in the hard drive of your computer. Cookies help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalized service.  
They enable us to:

•    Remember your login  
•    Recognize you when you return to our site  
•    Track web traffic on an aggregate basis (i.e. no individuals are identified)  
•    Track campaigns  
•    Keep session information such as your last search

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. Most browsers allow you to turn off cookies. However, switching off cookies will likely restrict your use of our website.

**Hotjar  
**  
This website uses services provided by Hotjar Ltd. Hotjar provides services including Heatmaps, Visitor recordings, Funnels and Form Analysis, Feedback Polls, Surveys and Recruiters. The information generated by the tracking code and cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Hotjar on servers in Ireland. Through the Hotjar tracking code the information collected includes:  

  *   **Device-specific data**

      The following information may be collected through your device and browser:

             o      your device's IP address (collected and stored in an anonymized format);  
             o      your email address including first name and last name;  
             o      device screen size;  
             o      device type (unique device identifiers) and browser information;  
             o      geographic location (country only);  
             o      preferred language used to display the webpage.  

  *   **Log data  
**  
  Our servers automatically record information which is created upon using Hotjar. Data  
  includes:

         o      referring domain;  
         o      pages visited;  
         o      geographic location (country only);   
         o      preferred language used to display the webpage;  
         o      date and time when website pages were accessed;

Hotjar will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Hotjar uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. By continuing to use this website, you consent to the processing of the above data by Hotjar and by the third parties used by Hotjar in accordance with their respective privacy policies. The cookies used by Hotjar have differing durations; some are 365 days, some persist for the session only.

To opt out please go to the following link:

<https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>

### Links to other websites

Please note that clicking on links and banner advertisements and RSS feeds may result in your transfer to another website, where data privacy practices may be different to this Privacy Policy. It is your responsibility to check other website privacy policies to ensure that you agree to your personal information  being used in accordance with those third parties privacy policies. We accept no responsibility for and have no control over third party websites, links, advertisements or RSS feeds or information that is submitted or collected by third parties.

### Change to our Privacy Policy

Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any time we decide to use Personal Data in a manner significantly different from that stated in this Privacy Policy, or otherwise disclosed to you at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in the new manner.

* * *

© Hays Specialist Recruitment 2000 - 2019. All rights reserved.
